

# David Abella Bujalance

Physicist. PhD candidate.



26 September 1997



Palma de Mallorca - Illes Balears Mobility: Available



+34 633 17 97 17



www.linkedin.com/in/david-abella-bujalance-a80512187



davidabbu@gmail.com

# Skills ——

Latex

Office

Fortran

Julia

Python

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

# Languages -

- · Catalan Native language
- Spanish Native language
- English Advanced level
- German Primary level (currently learning)

### Interests

As a physicist, my expertise lies in Statistical Mechanics and data analysis, offering a powerful toolkit to decipher complex problems. I'm driven by a passion for applying these skills to address global challenges and create meaningful change. Through critical thinking, I aim to create innovative solutions that lead to a brighter future.

### Work Experience

2023-2024 Research Technician at IFISC (CSIC)

Research associated with the project Nou Lloguer and Next4Mob to continue renting market data analysis and modelling.

2022-2023 Young researchers scholarship by SOIB (UIB)

Research focussed on different agent-based models of human dynamics.

2022 Research Technician at IFISC (CSIC)

Research associated with the project APASOS-CSIC and Nou Lloguer for the renting market data analysis.

2021 Predoctoral contract at IFISC

8-month contract to continue the study of aging effects in threshold models with application in sociotechnical systems. Focused on the study of aging in Noisy Schelling segregation Model.

#### Education

2021-2024 PhD candidate at the Institute of Cross-Disciplinary Physics and Complex Systems (IFISC)

PhD in thesis in Physics of Complex Systems applied to computational human dynamics.

2019 - 2020 M.Sc Physics of Complex Systems at Universitat de les Illes Balears Better understanding of the Complex Systems and Computational Social Science branch and the application of physics skills to an interdisciplinary scenario.

Master thesis: Perturbations propagation in self-organized patterns.

2015 - 2019 B.Sc Physics at Universitat de Barcelona

Acquisition of useful skills to model physical systems and solve problems. Minor in Fundamental Physics.

• Bachelor thesis: Many-Body body contributions in Water clusters (published in ACS Nano).

## Scientific publications

2024 Assesing the real estate spatial segmentation

(In submission)

2024 Ordering dynamics and aging in the symmetrical threshold model

New Journal of Physics. 26, 013033.

Aging in binary state models: the Threshold model for complex con-

tagion

Physical Review E. 107, 024101.

2023 Many-Body contributions in Water Nano-clusters

ACS Nano. 17 (3), 1959-1964.

2022 Aging effects in Schelling segregation model

Scientific Reports. 12, 19376.



# David Abella Bujalance

Physicist. PhD candidate.



26 September 1997



Palma de Mallorca - Illes Balears Mobility: Available



+34 633 17 97 17



www.linkedin.com/in/david-abella-bujalance-a80512187



davidabbu@gmail.com

# Skills -

Latex

Office

Fortran

Julia

Python

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

# Languages -

- Catalan Native language
- Spanish Native language
- English Advanced level
- German Primary level (currently learning)

### Collaboration and outreach events

Sep-2023 Associate researcher at Queen Mary University of London (QMUL)
Collaboration with Vincenzo Nicosia to study modeling techniques for spatial segregation.

2022-2023 Poster Party

Part of the Poster party comitee organizing the otreach event at IFISC.

Oct-2022 Conference of Complex Systems 2022

Volunteer and collaborator to the Conference on Complex Systems CCS 2022 in Palma.

### Supplementary Education

| 2023 | Participation at the Complexity72h Workshop |
|------|---|
|------|---|

2022 Summer school about Artificial Intelligence "Retos de la IA" by AIHUB-CSIC

2022 X Summer school on Statistical physics of Complex Systems by GEFENOL (at IFISC)

2022 II Summer school on Complex Socio-Technical systems by COM-

SOTEC (at IFISC)

2021 Introduction course to Artificial Intelligence at UBICS

## Scientific presentations

Feb-2024 Oral presentation "Assesing the real estate spatial segmentation" at CS3-24 (Barcelona - Spain)

July-2023 Oral presentation "Aging in binary state dynamics: Ordering in threshold models" at NetSci23 (Viena- Austria)

May-2023 Oral presentation "Aging in binary state dynamics: Ordering in threshold models" at CS3-23 (Santander - Spain)

Oct-2022 Oral presentation "Aging in binary-state models: Threshold model of complex contagion" at CCS2022 (Palma - Spain)

Sep-2022 Poster presentation "Aging in binary-state models" at II Summer school on Complex Socio-Technical systems (Palma - Spain)

Aug-2022 Poster presentation "Aging in binary-state models" at X Summer school on Statistical physics of Complex Systems (Palma - Spain)

May-2022 Poster presentation "Aging in Complex contagion" at FISES (Zaragoza - Spain)

Mar-2022 Oral presentation "Aging effects in Schelling segregation model" at COMSOTEC Workshop (Tarragona - Spain)

Oct-2021 Oral presentation "Aging effects in Schelling segregation model" at CCS2021 (Lyon - France)